(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T08:29:06.072129",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
初めまして 大好きな音楽へ
Nice to meet you, my beloved music,
ずっと考えてたこと
what I've been thinking about all this time,
どうか聞いてほしくって
I want you to hear it somehow.
伝えたいことがあるんです
There's something I want to tell you
ちょっと照れ臭いけれど
I'm a bit embarrassed about it, but
ずっと想っていたこと
what I've been thinking about all this time
こんなお手紙に込めて
I've put it all into this letter
届いてくれますように
May it make its way towards you
どんな時もあなたの
No matter when, your
言葉 声を聴いているだけで
Words, I'll only listen to your voice
力が湧いてくるんだ
As the power surges through me
ねぇ 笑っていたいよ どんな時も
Hey, I want to smile! No matter when
でも辛い 暗い 痛い日もある
There are still days, tough, dark, and painful
けどね あなたに触れるだけで気付けば
But you know, once I realize it, by touching you
この世界が色鮮やかになる
this world will become vividly colored
花が咲くように
As the flowers bloom
笑って泣いて どんな時だって
Smiling, crying, whenever it may be
選んでいいんだ いつでも自由に
Being able to always choose freely
今日はどんなあなたに出会えるかな
I wonder what kind of "you" I'll meet today
この世界が終わるその日まで
Until that day when the world ends
鳴り続けていて
Keep resounding
いつもあなたのことを求めちゃうんだ
Always ending up wanting more of you
踊り出したくなる時も
Even when it makes me want to break into a dance
爆発しちゃいそうな時も
Even when it seems like I'll explode
救われたんだ 支えられてきたんだ
Saved and sustained by you
心が動かされるんです
You make my heart move
心が満たされていくんです
You make my heart full
ねぇ もっと触れていたいよ
Hey, I want to experience you more
ずっとそばにいてほしいよ
I want you to be by my side forever
いつまでも 大好きなあなたが
Forever, my beloved
響いていますように
May you continue resounding
こんなたくさんの気持ち ぎゅっと詰め込んだ想い
All these overflowing feelings and tightly packed thoughts...
ちゃんと伝えられたかな ちょっとだけ不安だけど
I wonder if I conveyed them right. I'm just a little anxious, but...
きっと届いてくれたよね 全部私の素直な
I'm sure they reached you. Because these are all my honest...
言葉だから
...words.
もしもあなたに出会えてなかったなんて
Just thinking about what would have happened if I never met you...
思うだけで怖いほど大好きなんだ
scares me because I love you so much.
受け取ってどうか私の想いを
Please accept my feelings.
さあ笑って泣いてそんな毎日を
Come on, laughing and crying through every day,
歩いてくんだいついつまでも 辛い暗い痛いこともあるけど
we will keep walking forever and ever. There are plenty of hard, dark, and painful things, but...
この世界はいつでもどこでも音楽で溢れてる
this world is always and everywhere overflowing with music.
目の前のことも未来のことも 不安になってどうしたらいいの
Things right in front of us, the future, getting anxious and wondering what to do...
分かんなくって迷うこともあるけど
Even if there are times when I don't understand and get lost,
そんな時もきっとあなたがいてくれれば
I'm sure if you're there for me at times like that,
前を向けるんだ
I can look forward.
こんな気持ちになるのは こんな想いができるのは
Having feelings like this, having thoughts like this...
きっと音楽だけなんだ
must be because of music alone.
終わりなんてひとつもないんです どうか1000年先も
There is no such thing as an end. Please, even 1,000 years from now,
どうか鳴りやまないで いつも本当にありがとう
please don't stop playing. Thank you always, truly.
君が持ってきた漫画 くれた知らない名前のお花
The manga you brought, the flower with an unknown name you gave me.
今日はまだ来ないかな？
Won't you come today either?
初めての感情知ってしまった
I've come to know an emotion for the first time.
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって ひとり宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting decorated on the window, traveling through space alone.
それだけでも不自由ないけれど 僕は選んでみたいの
Even just that wouldn't be inconvenient, but I want to choose.
高鳴る心音だけの空を 安全なループを今書き換えて
A throbbing heart, a sky full of mysteries, rewriting the safe loop now.
君の手を握ってしまったら 孤独を知らないこの街には
If I were to hold your hand, to this city that knows no loneliness
もう二度と帰ってくることはできないのだろう
I probably won't ever be able to return again.
君が手を差し伸べた 光で影が生まれる
Shadows are born from the light where you reached out your hand.
歌って聞かせて この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story.
連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Take me away to a star I've never seen before.
誰の手も声も届かない 高くそびえ立った塔の上へ
To the top of a towering tower where no one's hands or voices can reach.
飛ばすフウセンカズラ 僕は君に笑ってほしいんだ
Flying balloon vine, I want you to smile.
満たされない穴は 惰性の会話や 澄ましたポーズで
The unfilled holes were filled until now with lazy conversations and aloof poses.
これまでは埋めてきたけれど
...
退屈な日々にサヨナラして 君と二人でこの街中を泳いできたら素敵でしょう？
Kicking away boring days, if the two of us could swim through this town, wouldn't that be wonderful?
出したこともないほど大きな声で やっと君に伝わる
With a louder voice than I've ever made, I finally reach you.
歪みくらいがさ 世界の端と端を結んで
A distortion is just right, tying the ends of the world together.
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって ひとり宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting decorated on the window, traveling through space alone.
それだけでも不自由ないけれど 僕は選んでみたいの
Even just that wouldn't be inconvenient, but I want to choose.
高鳴る心音だけの空を 安全なループを今書き換えて
A throbbing heart, a sky full of mysteries, rewriting the safe loop now.
君の手を握ってしまったら 孤独を知らないこの街には
If I were to hold your hand, to this city that knows no loneliness
もう二度と帰ってくることはできないのだろう いくらでも迷いながら
I probably won't ever be able to return again, no matter how much we get lost.
光も影も見に行こう
Let's go see both light and shadow.
歌って聞かせて この話の続き 連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story, take me away to a star I've never seen before.
世界の端と端を結んで
Tying the ends of the world together.
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって ひとり宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting decorated on the window, traveling through space alone.
それだけでも不自由ないけれど 僕は選んでみたいの
Even just that wouldn't be inconvenient, but I want to choose.
高鳴る心音だけの空を 安全なループを今書き換えて
A throbbing heart, a sky full of mysteries, rewriting the safe loop now.
君の手を握ってしまったら 孤独を知らないこの街には
If I were to hold your hand, to this city that knows no loneliness
もう二度と帰ってくることはできないのだろう
I probably won't ever be able to return again.
いくらでも迷いながら 光も影も見に行こう
No matter how much we get lost, let's go see both light and shadow.
歌って聞かせて この話の続き 連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story, take me away to a star I've never seen before.
世界の端と端を結んで
Tying the ends of the world together.
君が持ってきた漫画
The manga you brought with you,
くれた知らない名前のお花
and the flower with an unknown name you gave me.
今日はまだ来ないかな？
Will you still not come today?
初めての感情知ってしまった
I've come to know my very first emotions.
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって
Tracing the painting decorated by the window,
ひとり宇宙を旅して
I journey through space all alone.
君の手を握ってしまったら
If I were to hold your hand,
孤独を知らないこの街には
to this town that knows no loneliness,
もう二度と帰ってくることは
I would never be able to return again.
君が手を差し伸べた
You reached out your hand,
光で影が生まれる
and light gives birth to shadows.
歌って聞かせて この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story.
連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Take me away, to a star I've never seen before.
誰の手も声も届かない 高く聳え立った塔の上へ
To the top of the towering spire where no one's hands or voice can reach,
飛ばすフウセンカズラ
soaring balloon vine seeds.
僕は君に笑って欲しいんだ
I just want you to smile.
we can grow up ハイファイな talking box
We can grow up in a hi-fi talking box.
惹かれ合ってフレイム貼って calling night
Attracting each other, setting frames, calling night.
見たこともないくらいの未体験が
Unexperienced thrills like I've never seen before
浮き上がって止まないよ calling night
float up endlessly, calling night.
dance with me dance with you
認めたくない夜とまた
Once again with a night I don't want to admit,
ああ、どうこうだって言ってまた悩んでる
saying "oh, whatever" and worrying again.
どうしてんだろう、ぶちかます rainy day
What am I doing, crashing through a rainy day.
朝っぱらからまた brittany bitch
Right from early morning, once more, Brittany bitch.
90s湧くストレージゼロ
'90s stirring up, storage zero.
フィーリングはまた大気圏へ go up
Feelings go up into the atmosphere again.
dirty pop な friday night
A dirty pop Friday night.
イカして蒸して騒いで high
Looking cool, steaming up, getting rowdy and high.
take off 過ぎるアドベンチャータイム
An adventure time that's too much like takeoff.
weekend 遍く like sometimes
Spanning the weekend like sometimes.
calling it calling it calling it call up
ベンチレーション 未来はスローダウン
Ventilation, the future slows down.
ヒートアウトから徐々にウォームアップ
Gradually warming up from the heat out.
まだ濁る、dirt な弾丸
Still muddy, a dirty bullet.
ぶちかます rainy day
Crashing through a rainy day.
朝っぱらからまた brittany bitch
Right from early morning, once more, Brittany bitch.
90s milky way
今がインディペンデンスデイ
Right now is Independence Day.
we can grow up ハイファイな talking box
We can grow up in a hi-fi talking box.
混ざり合って対して calling night
Mixing together, facing each other, calling night.
見たこともないくらいの未体験が
Unexperienced thrills like I've never seen before
浮き上がって止まないよ calling night
float up endlessly, calling night.
dance with me dance with you
認めたくない夜とまた
Once again with a night I don't want to admit,
ああ、どうこうだって言ってまた悩んでる
saying "oh, whatever" and worrying again.
どうしてんだろう、ぶちかます rainy day
What am I doing, crashing through a rainy day.
朝っぱらからまた brittany bitch
Right from early morning, once more, Brittany bitch.
90s湧くストレージゼロ
'90s stirring up, storage zero.
フィーリングはまた大気圏へ go up
Feelings go up into the atmosphere again.
dirty pop な friday night
A dirty pop Friday night.
イカして蒸して騒いで high
Looking cool, steaming up, getting rowdy and high.
take off 過ぎるアドベンチャータイム
An adventure time that's too much like takeoff.
weekend 遍く like sometimes
Spanning the weekend like sometimes.
calling it calling it calling it call up
ベンチレーション 未来はスローダウン
Ventilation, the future slows down.
ヒートアウトから徐々にウォームアップ
Gradually warming up from the heat out.
まだ濁る、dirt な弾丸
Still muddy, a dirty bullet.
イェーイ！みんなー！今日応援しに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Yay! Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to cheer me on today!
どうだった？どうだった？なんかさ、
How was it? How was it? You know,
1周年の時よりは緊張しなかった。あの、なんだろうな、なんかこう、いっぱい練習したしみたいな。
I was less nervous than my 1st anniversary. Um, how should I put it, like, I practiced so much and all.
もうその直前までね、リハもやってたし、いっぱい練習したし、なんか、前と、まあでもそこ条件変わんないか、変わんないけどなんかすごい緊張しなかったです。イェーイ！イェーイ！
Right up until right before, I was doing rehearsals, practiced a lot, and somehow—well, conditions didn't really change, but I wasn't super nervous. Yay! Yay!
なんだ、なんだ、なんだ。よかった？ありがとう！ありがとうございまーす！
What, what, what. Was it good? Thank you! Thank you so much!
ちょっとね、「ラブレター」はみんなに対してね、初めましてって、その1曲目っていうので初めましてって気持ちとかね、あとみんなに、あの、こういう想いがあるんだよっていうのを伝えたいなと思って選びました。
You see, I chose "Love Letter" because I wanted to convey my "nice to meet you" feelings since it's the first song, and let everyone know that I hold these feelings for you.
そして、えー2曲目の「花の塔」もですね、あの非常に可愛らしい曲で、作本とめっちゃリコリコ好きでさ、この曲超好きなんだけど、
And for the second song, "Hana no Tou," it's such an adorable song, and Sakumoto and I love LycoReco so much, I super love this song,
これもね、なんかみんなと一緒にね、こう、なんだろうな、走り出すじゃないけど、一緒にこれからもね、側にほしいなっていう気持ちも込めて選びました！イェーイ！
and I chose it with the feeling that I want to—not quite start running together with everyone, but stay close by your side from now on! Yay!
うーん、揺れがすごいんだよね
Hmm, the shaking is intense.
そしてですね、えー3曲目のトーキングボックスはですね、
And then, um, the third song, "Talking Box",
あれめちゃ良くない？
wasn't that like, super good?
なんか、さらっと挟まるやつね
You know, that one that just slips right in,
めちゃめちゃいいでしょ？
isn't it super nice?
あれもね、すごい頑張って撮りましたので、
I worked really hard on filming that too,
はい、見てもらえて嬉しいななんて余ってありますみんなありがとうね、よかったでしょ
so yeah, I'm so happy you watched it. Thank you everyone, wasn't it great?
ではですね、えー沙花叉クロヱ今日お誕生日っていうことでみんなにねたくさんお祝いしてほしいのでだな、
Now then, um, since today is Sakamata Chloe's birthday, I want everyone to celebrate lots, so,
えーお祝いする時のツイートのタグはですねこちらですじゃじゃーん！
um, the tweet tag for celebrating is right here, ta-da!
見えるかい？
Can you see it?
こちら、えー沙花叉クロヱ生誕祭ライブでつぶやいてください！ぜひトレンド1位にね
Right here, please tweet with the hashtag Sakamata Chloe Birthday Live! Please make it
そしてください。
trending #1.
お祝い、そうお祝いは絶対絶対だよ、絶対絶対。
Celebrations—yes, celebrations are an absolute must, absolutely.
さあ、さあ、ということでですね、ちょっと疲れてきちゃったんですけども、早いんですけどまだ、
Now, now, with that being said, um, I got a bit worn out, but even though it's early,
えーちょっとね、なんか、また、なんか知ってるような気がするんですけど、
um, wait, it feels like I've seen this before, but
ちょっととあるものをですね、水族館に特別にご用意してくださったらしく、ちょっと移動しちゃいますか？移動させていただきます。
apparently they specially prepared something for me at the aquarium, so shall we move there? I'll have you move.
ちょっとじゃあ水族館にみんなで行くぞ。行きますよ。
Alright, let's all go to the aquarium together. Here we go.
沙花叉からのラブレター、読んでほしいな。
I want you to read a love letter from Sakamata.
はい、これ。
Here you go.
はい、ということで
Alright, and so
移動してきましたー！どうもどうもどうも！
we have moved here! Hello, hello, hello!
えー沙花叉からのラブレター読んでくれましたか？どうだった？
Um, did you read the love letter from Sakamata? How was it?
沙花叉ね、ずっと頑張って書いたんだけれども、あの、こんなね2分半もかかるとは思っていませんでした（笑）
Sakamata wrote it working so hard, but um, I didn't think it would take 2 and a half minutes, lol!
皆さん、2分半の間にね読めだかと思うんですがね、はい、ありがとうございます。
Everyone, I think you managed to read it within 2 and a half minutes, yep, thank you very much.
よかったでしょ。
Wasn't it nice?
ではですね、ちょっと、どう、どうですか？この水族館みんなさ、あの、ちょっと知ってる人は知っているなんですけど、実はね沙花叉水族館イベントをやっていたんですが、最近に
Now then, um, how is it? This aquarium, everyone, um, well, those who know know, but actually, Sakamata was running an aquarium event recently,
そのね、元になったアクアパーク品川さんをね、元に、元にしてこのステージを作ったんですけど、水族館のね、その時の映像ももう行けなかったよっていう子のために用意しております。
and we made this stage based on Aqua Park Shinagawa, and we prepared footage from that time at the aquarium for those who couldn't go.
あれ？
Huh?
さらっと出せよ
Just bring it out smoothly,
あれ、あれ？このボタンは、あ、ねえねえねえねえ、もしや…ってやつですかね？
lol! Huh, huh? This button, oh hey hey hey hey, could it be... that kind of thing?
これ、そ、そうだなぁ。
Well, let's see...
いい、いいんすかこれ？
Is this really okay?
回しちゃっていいんすか自分？
Can I go ahead and spin it?
ちょっと絶好調スロットだよねこれ
This slot machine is in top form, right?
じゃあちょっといきますよ。
Alright, here we go.
電源！オン！
Power! On!
あれ？
Huh?
つかない？
It won't turn on?
つく？
Will it?
つかない！
It won't turn on!
おい！電源オン！
Hey! Power on!
電源！オン！
Power! On!
どうだ...
How's that...
あれ！つかない！
Huh! It won't turn on!
くそ！な、なんでだ？なんか付かないぞ。で、電源が足りない？
Damn! W-Why? Is there not enough power?
じゃ、もう最後の気合の蹴りで行くわ。電源！オン！
Well, one last kick of spirit. Power! On!
オン！
On!
ああ、ついた！
Ah, it turned on!
ああ、びっくりした。事故ったかと思った。
Ah, I was scared. Thought it malfunctioned.
はい、というわけでですね、ちょっと坂また恒例のスロットタイムということで回します！
Right, as usual for Sakamata, it's slot time!
ティルン！
Tirun!
あ、バーが来て...
Ah, a bar came up...
お、おー！？フリーズ引きちゃんだけど！
Oh, whoa!? I hit a freeze!
え！？大丈夫？このスロットやばすぎない？壊れ台なんだけどフリーズ引きましたね。
Eh!? Is this a broken machine? I hit a freeze.
ちょっと、え、坂またもしかして初っ端から当たってる？え？これ、当たってってこと？え、いいの？
Did I hit it right from the start? Is this okay?
え、いいんですか？あ、なんだ？なんだ？ただの事故か？あ、そうだよね。はい。
Eh, is it? Just an accident? Ah, right. Yes.
初手からのさ、に、2回目のこの真ん中でだいたいわかるんよね、もう。当たんないなとかさ。
You can usually tell by the second middle spin.
あ、おい、お？や、や、や、はい。まあまあまあまあ、どうなるんすか？
Ah, hey, oh? Well, how's it going to turn out?
ねえ！坂またのおもちゃ、本当壊れてる！
Hey! Sakamata's toy is totally broken!
ちゃん、ちゃんと遊びたいのに！ひどい！ひどい！
Even though I wanted to play properly! Awful!
ちょっと、どういうことなんですか？このホール。訴えますよ。
Wait, what is the meaning of this arcade?
なぁ、じょーじょーしたんだろ？訴えてやる！
Hey, you joked around, didn't you? I'll sue you!
お、スイカきてよ。え、これスイカ？
Oh, watermelons coming. Is this a watermelon?
おおー！ちゃんとスイカ拾いましたね。バーじゃないやつや。
Whoa! I got the watermelon, not a bar.
え、クロエチャレンジ？何それ！？そんな作ったの？ねえ？ちゃんと打ってる人じゃん。
Eh, Chloe Challenge? You actually made that?
え、これしかもうホロックスのロゴやん。後ろに付いてるの。何クロエチャレンジ？
Eh, it's just the HoloX logo on the back.
え、どうなるのどうなるの？いいのかこれ？入るのかなクロエチャレンジに。
Eh, how will it turn out? Will it enter?
なるほどね、こっちからか。はいはいはい。右からね。７を狙え。はい。はい。はい。はい！
I see. From the right. Aim for 7. Yes!
え！？フリーズ！？フリーズじゃん！フリーズじゃんこれ！でもたまにフリーズで外れるよね。どっち？
Eh!? It's a freeze! But sometimes you miss.
帰ろっかな。もう帰っちゃおっかな。お誕生日やけどもう帰っちゃおっかな。
Shall I just go home? It's my birthday, but...
フリーズって言って出たのに、嘘つき！
You said it was a freeze, liar!
え！？フリーズ！？フリーズですか？これ！？
Eh!? Is this a freeze!?
フリーズ！？ででも待て...当たってるーー！
Freeze!? But wait... I hit it!
ちょっと待て、発展したんだけど！発展とかあるのこのスロットに。
Wait, it progressed! There's progression?
え？なになに？すごい！黄色の黄色の役が、ねえ？ど、どうなるんだい？
What's this? Amazing! What's gonna happen?
頼む！頼む！並んで頼む！頼む！頼む！並んで頼む！トリプルセブンで頼む！頼む！
Please! Line up! Triple Seven, please!
いっしょに？ う〜っ、かもん！
Together? Woo, c'mon!
ホロライブからこんにちは
Hello from Hololive!
うまくいきすぎちゃってすいません
Sorry for things going a bit too well.
追い風ぎゅっと背に受けて
With the tailwind tight on my back,
いくぜ！とんとんとん拍子で
Let's go smoothly, step by step!
Go!
ぴちぴちハネるぜ名古屋城
Splashing lively at Nagoya Castle,
くるくるぱっと回ってのぼり龍
Spinning around and around, the ascending dragon.
センパイ方のチカラ借り
Borrowing the seniors' power,
のってみせるぜでかいビッグウェーブ！
I'll ride a huge big wave!
ねえわたしたち ほんとツイてるから
Hey, we're really feeling lucky,
ラッキー らっきー らっきー
Lucky, lucky, lucky!
いただいちゃいます！
I'll take it all!
今日もカクヘンがとまらない！
Today's fever mode still won't stop!
キセキを起こしまくれ！
Stir up a storm of miracles!
いっさいがっさい
Everything, all of it,
いただいちゃえ！
I'll snatch it all up!
運も実力のうちだもんね
After all, luck is part of skill too.
あれもこれもどれもこれも
That, this, and everything else—
ほしくなってこまっちゃう
I want it all and it's troubling me.
かっさらっちゃえ！
Just swipe it all!
ごちそうさま！ 神サマもーっとくださいな
Thanks for the meal! Dear God, please give me even more.
トリプルセブン
Triple Seven!
もももも！ (とーぷーっ！)
Momomomo! (To-pu-!)
おしとやかなフリしてみて
Trying to act all graceful and modest,
熱いハートはいつも燃えさかる
my passionate heart is always blazing.
この世の道楽はガッテン承知
I'm well aware of the world's pleasures.
どんなラッキーも勝手にはやってこない！
No luck is ever going to just come on its own!
みんなホントはもー特訓してるんだ
Everyone's actually been training hard in secret.
そうさ
That's right!
ゼッタイぜったいぜったい願いは叶う！
Absolutely, positively, our wishes will come true!
今日もカクヘンをとめさせない！
Keep the fever mode going today too!
キセキを手繰りよせろ！
Pull those miracles in close!
あそれアッパレ！ そうだアッパレ！
Bravo! Yes, magnificent!
運は努力でつかみとるんだ
Luck is something you seize through hard work.
君がいるからがんばれる
I can do my best because you're here.
今すぐにお返ししたい！あげるよラッキー！
I want to repay you right now! Have some luck!
みんなでハッピー！ ずっと当て続けみせる
Happy with everyone! I'll keep winning continuously.
ずっと当て続けみせる
I'll keep on hitting the jackpot.
トリプルセブン
Triple Seven!
もももも！
Momomomo!
もしもいいことなくなってね
Even if nothing good happens for a while,
そのぶんでっかいラッキーが
that just means an equally huge amount of luck
君のこと待っているんだよ
is waiting out there for you.
だから
So—
信じ続けていればきっといいことあるさ
If you keep believing, something good is bound to happen.
この気持ち君にとどけたいから
I want to deliver these feelings straight to you,
君の声たくさんききたいから
and hear your voice so many times over.
もっともっともっともっともっともっとずっとついてきて！
More, more, more, more! Keep following right along with me!
もうもうとめられな〜〜い！！
There's just no stopping us anymore!!
今日もカクヘンがとまらない！
Today's fever mode still won't stop!
キセキを起こしまくれ！
Stir up a storm of miracles!
いっさいがっさい いただいちゃえ！
Everything, all of it—I'll take it all!
運も実力のうちだもんね
After all, luck is part of skill too.
あれもこれもどれもこれも
That, this, and everything else—
ほしくなってこまっちゃう
I want it all and it's troubling me.
かっさらっちゃえ！ ごちそうさま！
Swipe it all! Thanks for the meal!
神サマもーっとくださいな
Dear God, please give me even more.
トリプルセブン
Triple Seven!
もももも！
Momomomo!
君に捧ぐ
Dedicated to you,
トリプルセブン！
Triple Seven!
へぇい、がんばり涙流すじゃない？
Hey, aren't those tears from trying hard?
へぇい、がんがん涙流すじゃない？
Hey, crying your eyes out non-stop?
それで平気なフリは普通じゃない
Acting like it's totally fine isn't normal at all.
言いたいことあるのに
Even though you've got things you want to say,
抱え込んだモヤモヤはどこに
where do you hide all that bottled-up gloom?
ねぇいつか急に溢れて
Hey, someday it'll suddenly overflow—
「ごめんもうダメ助けて」って
"I'm sorry, I can't take it, please help me!"
想像したくもない 聞きたくないじゃない
That's something I never want to imagine or hear.
だからそうな前に頼っちゃえよ
So before it gets to that, just rely on me!
叶えたい夢を胸にギュッと詰めて
Stuff all your cherished dreams tight inside your chest,
「僕ら止まれない」これはいい感じですか?
"We can't stop!" Does this feel right?
やっぱりダメでしょうか?
Or is it a total failure?
終わらない夜は 星と踊って話そう
On this endless night, let's dance with the stars and talk.
ツラいときも光はずっと側に
Even when it hurts, the light is always right by your side.
「僕ら止まれない」君も大丈夫になる
"We can't stop!" You'll be alright too,
ピッタリ笑顔になるから
'cause your smile will fit you perfectly.
まだまだこれじゃ足りないや
There's still not enough of this yet!
言いたい言葉間違いえないように
So I don't mess up the words I want to say,
「無理は禁止します」「僕はここにいます」
"No pushing yourself too hard," "I'm right here."
明日に凹まされないように また笑い合えたら
So tomorrow doesn't get you down, if we can smile together again—
「僕ら止まれない」これはいい感じですか?
"We can't stop!" Does this feel right?
やっぱりダメでしょうか?
Or is it really no good after all?
終わらない夜は 星と踊って話そう
On this endless night, let's dance with the stars and talk,
ツラいときも光はずっと側に
Even when it's tough, light is always by your side.
「僕ら止まれない」君も大丈夫になる
"We can't stop!" You'll be alright too,
ピッタリ笑顔になるから
'cause your smile will fit you perfectly.
間違ってなんかないのに
Even though you haven't done anything wrong,
誰かが「違う」って言うんなら
if someone tells you that you're wrong—
君を否定してしまうすべてを
everything that tries to deny who you are,
僕は肯定なんかしないから
I will never validate or accept it.
抱き締めついででもいいからさ
Even if it's just as an excuse to hold you close,
不安も僕に流してよ
let all your anxieties flow into me.
恥ずかしいって言うけれどさ
You might say it's embarrassing, but hey,
それは僕も一緒なんだよ
I feel the exact same way too.
似合ってないとか笑うなよ
Don't laugh and say it doesn't suit me—
君に会えたことへの答えだよ
this is my answer to having met you.
頼ってくれ 頼ってくれ どうか
So rely on me, please rely on me, won't you?
叶えたい夢を胸にギュッと詰めて
Stuff all your cherished dreams tight inside your chest,
「僕ら止まれない」これはいい感じですか?
"We can't stop!" Does this feel right?
やっぱりダメでしょうか?
Or is it really no good after all?
終わらない夜は 星と踊って話そう
On this endless night, let's dance with the stars and talk,
ツラいときも光はずっと側に
Even when it's tough, light is always by your side.
「僕ら止まれない」君も大丈夫になる
"We can't stop!" You'll be alright too,
ピッタリ笑顔になるから
'cause your smile will fit you perfectly.
まだまだこれじゃ足りないや
There's still not enough of this yet!
言いたい言葉間違いえないように
So I don't mess up the words I want to say,
「無理は禁止します」「僕はここにいます」
"No pushing yourself too hard," "I'm right here."
明日に凹まされないように また笑い合えたら
So tomorrow doesn't get you down, if we can smile together again—
「僕ら止まれない」
"We can't stop!"
頼ってくれ 頼ってくれ どうか
So rely on me, please rely on me, won't you?
叶えたい夢を胸にギュッと詰めて
Stuff all your cherished dreams tight inside your chest,
「僕ら止まれない」これはいい感じですか?
"We can't stop!" Does this feel right?
やっぱりダメでしょうか?
Or is it really no good after all?
終わらない夜は 星と踊って話そう
On this endless night, let's dance with the stars and talk,
ツラいときも光はずっと側に
Even when it's tough, light is always by your side.
「僕ら止まれない」君も大丈夫になる
"We can't stop!" You'll be alright too,
ピッタリ笑顔になるから
'cause your smile will fit you perfectly.
まだまだこれじゃ足りないや
There's still not enough of this yet!
言いたい言葉間違いえないように
So I don't mess up the words I want to say,
「無理は禁止します」「僕はここにいます」
"No pushing yourself too hard," "I'm right here."
明日に凹まされないように また笑い合えたら
So tomorrow doesn't get you down, if we can smile together again—
「僕ら止まれない」君も大丈夫になる
"We can't stop!" You'll be alright too,
ピッタリ笑顔になるから
'cause your smile will fit you perfectly.
から…
...because.
どうだった？
How was it?
ちょっと沙花叉初のオリジナルソングということで、
Since it's Sakamata's very first original song...
ホロックスに来ててもらいました！ありがとうございます！
I had them come to HoloroX! Thank you so much!
ちょっとめちゃめちゃ可愛くみんなね、
Everyone was just so, so cute,
そしてあの、意味を持たせてできたんじゃないかなと思うので
and I think we managed to give it a lot of meaning too.
またこれも今度お話したりしてね。
So we can talk about this again sometime.
ちょっと感謝の気持ちをお伝えしたいなと思って
I wanted to convey my feelings of gratitude,
感謝と言えばこれですよね。
and speaking of gratitude, this is it, right?
じゃあ、あなたも！
So, here you go, you too!
これ、なんだかわかりますかね？
I wonder if you know what this is?
ちょっと浮かばない、とある曲が。そしてゴンドラがここにあるということで、はい、いきたいと思います。
Well, a certain song comes to mind, and since there's a gondola right here, yes, let's go.
愛を込めて、あなたも！
With all my love, here you go!
二人で写真を撮ろう 懐かしいこの景色と
Let's take a picture together with this nostalgic scenery,
あの日と同じポーズでおどけてみせて欲しい
and I want you to act silly in that same pose as that day.
見上げる空の青さを気まぐれに雲は流れ キレイなものは遠くにあるからキレイなの
Looking up at the blue sky, clouds drift whimsically; beautiful things are beautiful because they're far away.
約束したとおりあなたとここに来れて本当に良かったわ
I'm so truly glad we could come here together just as we promised.
この込み上げる感情が愛じゃないなら何が愛かわからないほど
If this surging feeling isn't love, then I don't know what love is.
愛をこめて花束を 大袈裟だけど受け取って
I'm giving you a bouquet with all my love—it's extravagant, but please accept it.
理由なんて訊かないでよね
Please don't ask me for any reasons.
今だけすべて忘れて 笑わないで受け入れて 照れていないで
Just forget everything for now, accept it without laughing, and don't be shy.
二人で写真を撮ろう
Let's take a picture together
懐かしいこの景色と
With this nostalgic scenery
あの日と同じポーズで
Striking the same pose as that day
おどけてみせてほしい
I want you to playfully show me
見上げる空の青さを
Looking up at the blue sky
気まぐれに雲は流れ
Where whimsical clouds drift by
キレイなものは遠くにあるから
Beautiful things are far away
キレイなの
Because they are beautiful
約束したとおりあなたと
Just as we promised, being with you
ここに来れて本当に良かったわ
Here has truly been wonderful
この込み上がる気持ちが
If this overflowing feeling
愛じゃないなら
Isn't love,
何が愛かわからないほど
I wouldn't know what love is
愛をこめて花束を
With love, a bouquet
大げさだけど受け取って
It may be exaggerated, but accept it
理由なんて訊かないでね
Don't ask for reasons
今だけすべて忘れて
Just forget everything for now
笑わないで受けとめて
Don't laugh, just accept it
照れていないで
Don't be shy
昨日とよく似た今日は
Yesterday and today, at the crossroads
何気ない分かれ道を
I understood the casual parting ways
わかって選び損ねた
But I hesitated in choosing
臆病のせいでしょう
Out of cowardice
私は泣くのが得意で
I'm good at crying
最初から慰めを当てにしてたわ
I've always relied on comfort from the start
何度も間違った道 選び続けて
Choosing the wrong path many times,
正しくここに戻ってきたの
I've finally returned here correctly.
巡り巡る時を越えて
Beyond the passing of time,
いつもあなたのところへと
I always return to you.
この心舞い戻ってゆく
My heart always comes back to you.
無理に描く理想より
Rather than forcing an ideal,
笑い合える今日の方が
Today, being able to laugh together
ずっと幸せね
Is much happier.
violet, indigo, black and blue
flame, yellow, purple, sky blue
pink, yellow green, ash, brown......
あなたに贈る色は......?
What is the color I send to you......?
巡り巡る時を越えて
Beyond the passing of time,
いつもあなたのところへと
I always return to you.
この心舞い戻ってゆく
My heart always comes back to you.
ありがとうも言い出せずに
Without being able to say thank you,
甘えていた 今日ここに来るまでは
I was being spoiled until I came here today.
愛をこめて花束を
With love, a bouquet
大げさだけど受け取って
It may be exaggerated, but accept it
理由なんて訊かないでね
Don't ask for reasons
今だけすべて忘れて
Just forget everything for now
笑わないで受けとめて
Don't laugh, just accept it
本当の私を
Me, for who I really am
いつまでもそばにいて
Stay with me forever and ever
どうだったかなみんな！
How was it, everyone?!
坂又の気持ち、ちょっと本当に投げさせていただきました！ありがとうございます！
I really poured my feelings out to you! Thank you so much!
いや坂又ね、本当に普段からみんなにはね、感謝をしていて
You know, I'm always so grateful to everyone,
ちょっとお言葉をお伝えするのは下手っぴなのであんまり言えないのですが
and I'm not good at expressing my feelings in words so I can't say much, but...
あのいつも、ありがとうございます。
um, always, thank you so much.
大好きです。本当です。
I love you. Really.
あっ、あれだ、なんかのお誕生日の お祝いなのに
Ah, wait, even though it's my birthday celebration,
なんか足りないな！もっとなんかお誕生日には
something's missing! For my birthday, I want something more,
欲しいな、ね、もっともっと、もっともらえるよね
right? More and more, I should get more, right?
じゃあちょっと、みんな言いました？
So everyone, did you say it?
ちょっと次のステージに行こうかな！
Shall we move on to the next stage?!
行きますよ！せーの！レッツゴー！
Here we go! Ready, set, let's go!
最初に坂又なんかあの振り付けでまだ出てきてないかもしれないんですけど
First off, I might not have even debuted this with choreography yet...
あのまだ出てきてないですけどこういうね
Um... well, it hasn't appeared yet, but see, something like this...
見て見て、これ
Look, look at this.
これなんか見たことない？みんな
Haven't you guys seen this before, everyone?
反復横跳びなんですよね
It's side-to-side jumping.
あのダンサーさんに教わったんです。反復横跳びの要領でやればいいんですよって言われて反復横跳びって言ったら教えてもらって
I learned it from the dancer. They told me, "Just do it like side-to-side jumping," and when I said "side-to-side jumping," they taught me.
これだからできるの坂又。見てて。きょうせーの
So that's why Sakamata can do it. Watch. Ready...
せーの
Go!
ほら！できる！どう？
See? I can do it! How's that?
できてる？できてりよね？
Did I do it? I did it, right?
成長したかなくない？ほら、ほらね？
Didn't I grow? Look, see?
いやだいぶ1回はできるようになった。すごいでしょ？
Man, I can actually do it once now. Pretty amazing, right?
おめでとうって。すごいでしょ？すごいでしょ？
Say "congrats!" Isn't it amazing? Isn't it?
そしてね、あともう一つできるようになったことがあるんですよ。測点いきますよ。
And you know, there's another thing I learned to do. Let's do a cartwheel.
はっ！よっしゃ！できたな。
Ha! Alright! I did it.
完璧でしたね。完璧だったよね、みんな。
That was perfection. It was perfect, right everyone?
あ、疲れちゃった。おしまい。疲れちゃった。
Ah, I'm tired. That's it. I got tired.
ああ、誕生日になんちゃん。
Ah, on my birthday...
ああ、みんなありがとうございます。今日いっぱいお祝いしてもらい、ありがと。エゴサもね、坂本してたのですが
Ah, thank you everyone. Thank you so much for celebrating with me today. I was ego-searching too, Sakamata was doing that, but...
みんながなんかあのケーキを作ってくれたりとかあとあれもいたら、あのピクセルアートみたいですごっかいデッカイやつ作ってくれたりとかだし
Everyone made cakes for me, or made huge pixel art pieces and stuff...
あとね、すごいね、グッズの祭壇みたいなのも作ってくれたりくれたりもいたのね。だから本当に嬉しかったりします。
And also, you guys even made altar-like setups of my merch. So I'm really, really happy.
これからもね、坂方のことたくさん愛してね。そして今日は本当に緊張のガチガチ緊張なので
From now on too, please love Sakamata a lot. And today I'm super, super nervous, super stiff with tension,
よかったらみんな、あのコメントでもね、見てるよ、応援してるよ、頑張れって言ってもらえたら嬉しいです。緊張。
so if you'd like, everyone, in the comments too—"I'm watching," "I'm cheering," "You can do it"—if you tell me that, I'll be so happy. I'm so nervous.
では、あの坂方頑張りますので応援してちょうだい。バイバイ！
Well then, Sakamata will do her best, so please cheer me on. Bye-bye!
はーい！というわけで、フェステージにやってきちゃいました！いえーい！
Hii! And with that, we've arrived at the Fes stage! Yay!
ちょっと見て見て！これすごくない？フェステージ、めちゃめちゃかっこいいよね！
Just look, look! Isn't this amazing? The Fes stage is so super cool!
ロック、そう、ロックだよね。坂方と言えばロックでしょ、みんな。
Rock, yeah, it's rock. Speaking of Sakamata, it's rock, right everyone?
初めて来たかもだけど、すごくない？見て！めっちゃきれいなんですけど！
This might be your first time here, but isn't it amazing? Look! It's so pretty!
すごーい！しかもね、ちゃんと客席に皆さんがいらっしゃるんですよ。
So amazing! And look, everyone is actually here in the audience seats.
ちょっと見れるかな？みんなここにそう！めちゃめちゃずらーと、おらおらおら、うわあ！怖いね！
Can we see? Everyone here—right! So many—woah, woah, woah! Ah, it's scary!
相変わらず怖いんだね、みんなね。なんでそんな顔つきちゃったのかなって毎回思いますね。やだなぁ。何度見ても嫌だな、ビビってます。はい。
You guys are as scary as ever. I always wonder why you made such faces. Oh well. No matter how many times I see it, I hate it, I'm scared. Yes.
というわけでね、この後ちょっとライブをしていきたいんですけど
So, after this, I'd like to do a little live performance, but...
フェスって言ったらあれ欲しくないですか？あれ？わかるみんな？ね、あれ、あれ！みんなちょっと言って今コメントで。わかるっしょ？
when I say "fes," don't you want "that"? "That"? Do you guys know? Right, "that," "that"! Everyone, type it in the chat right now. You know it, right?
あれ、あれ欲しいよね！フェスと言えば何ですか？大喜利じゃないからね（笑）。
Right, you want "that," right? When you say "fes," what is it? It's not an ogiri joke.
フェスと言えばなんだ、なんだ。どういうこと？
Speaking of a fes, what is it? What's going on?
みんなフェスをまず、大丈夫かな、わかってるかな？サイリウム？あー、違うね。
Everyone, first about the fes—is it okay, do you understand? Penlight? Ah, no.
ま、そのサイリウムも、フルタイプのフェスもあるけどね。わかるわかる。はい。
Well, there are full-type penlight fests too. I get it, I get it. Yes.
あ、そう！え、よくわかったね！そうなんですよ！これなんだ、これみんな。これ、これなんだ、これ。そう！ギターなんですよ！ギター欲しいの、坂方！
Ah, right! Eh, you figured it out! That's right! What is this, everyone? This—what is this? Right! It's a guitar! Sakamata wants a guitar!
ちょっと運営さん、みんなも言ってしい、坂方も欲しいから、あの男スプレゼントにギターください。ギター。ギター。
Management, everyone say it too, Sakamata wants one, so please give me a guitar as a birthday present. A guitar. A guitar.
ところかこ？え、やった！もらえるってこと？
Treasure chest? Eh, really! Does that mean I get it?
あ、鍵？鍵つてじゃないけど、え、鍵は？
Ah, a key? It's not a key... Eh, where's the key?
鍵？鍵は？え、なんだ、鍵は？え、なんだ、鍵は？え、なんだこれ？
Key? Where's the key? Eh, what, where's the key? Eh, what is this?
沙花叉ギターゲットチャレンジ
[Visual: Sakamata Guitar Get Challenge]
ね、そういうのいいから、そういうのいいから、ちょうだい！ねえ、ギター欲しいの！ねえ、何にそれっていうか、な、なにするのまず？何させられるの？
Hey, enough of that kind of stuff, just give it to me! Hey, I want a guitar! Hey, what's with that—first, what am I going to do? What am I being made to do?
大爆笑！画像大喜利10連発
[Visual: Roaring Laughter! 10 Consecutive Image Ogiri]
ざけんな！ざけんな！大爆笑なんて文字を使うなそんで、えー
Are you kidding me?! Don't use words like "roaring laughter" like that, and...
これどうどうどうどうしたらいいの？
What on earth should I do here?
え、坂方ってか画像大喜利を十連発するの？
Eh, doing 10 consecutive image grand prix?
皆さん、地獄のような時間、ちょっとやめてもらっていいですか？
Everyone, can you please stop this hellish time?
歌いたいな。なんか何度も歌いたくなる。わ、わがままとしちゃあ
I want to sing. Somehow I want to sing it over and over. Well, as my selfishness...
じゃあ、い、行きますか？あの、1枚目とかあるんですかね？
Well, shall we go? Um, are there things like the first one?
じゃあ1枚目どうぞ！
Well then, the first one, please!
ああ…え？えっと…
Ah... Eh? Um...
ああ、そろそろこの御曹司役のもあきてきたな。
Ah, I'm getting tired of this scion role.
2枚目。
The second one.
ああ、さっきの「が」が入ってんだよな。「が」が入ってんだよな。
Ah, the "ga" from earlier is in there. The "ga" is in there.
「が」が！「が」が入ってんだよな！
"Ga"! The "ga" is in there!
厳しいな！はい、次。
That's harsh! Next, please.
バック・トゥ・ザ・フューチャー
Back to the Future...
でないか。そうよね。良くないしね、しかも。はい、次。
Not quite. That's right. It's not good either, plus. Next.
ああ、あー、あー、あー！
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
なんのこれしき！え？やばい。
Nothing to this! Eh? Oh no.
次、次、次！次！
Next, next, next! Next!
あなたを殺せば最後なのよね？だめ、だめ。
If I kill you, it's the end, right? No, no.
くそっ、次。
Damn it, next.
見てみて！おやしきにちが入った！
Look, look! Oyakishi-ni-chi entered!
おい行けよ！え、そう、誰が笑ったの今の？え、行きなんだ！やった！おやしきです！行きました！やった！
Hey go! Eh, right, who laughed just now? Eh, you're going! Yay! It's Oyakishi! I went! Yay!
え何、なんかせっかくだからもうちょっとの受け取ってくださいって言われたんだけどな。えー、じゃあどうぞどうぞ、もう全部使いたいよの、そこ。
Eh what, since it's a special occasion, they told me to accept a bit more. Eh, well go ahead, go ahead, I want to use all of it, right there.
家族の命がかかってるんだ！
My family's lives are on the line!
ああ、いいんだ！それいいんだ！それも許されるんだ！はいはいはい、はい次。
Ah, that's fine! That's fine! That's allowed too! Right right right, yes next.
えーー
Ehーー
わかんない！同じ気持ちなんだってよ、その時の一言。わかんないよ！むずい！何やりらされて…
I don't get it! They said they feel the same way at that moment. I don't get it! It's so hard! What am I being made to do...
スロットですってらっしゃる。
Playing slots with a headache.
いや、付けたいんだよ！黒字なんだけどな。あ、いいんだ、それはいいんだ。へえ、基準がわからんのだ。
No, I want to attach it! It's in the black though. Ah, that's fine, that's fine. Huh, I don't understand the criteria.
ラストらしいです。
It seems to be the last one.
これすれば餌もらえるんだよな！オッケー！
If I do this, I can get food! Okay!
坂上の気持ちですか。これ、これすれば餌もらえるんだよな。ありがとうございます！
Sakagami's feelings. If I do this, I can get food. Thank you very much!
どうも！地獄の企画につき合わせてしまいすみません。本当はあの、事前に何も教えてもらわずになんか突然バーンって出されたやつなんでね。あの、坂本も動揺しておりますが、
Thank you! I'm sorry for making you put up with this hellish project. Actually, without telling me anything beforehand, it was suddenly thrust upon me. Sakamata is also flustered, but
これでじゃあ坂本！鍵ゲットしたんですか？ちょうだい！ちょうだいちょうだい、鍵は？鍵もらったの坂本？持ってるー！すごーい！
With this, Sakamata! Did you get the key? Give it to me! Give it to me, where's the key? Did you get the key, Sakamata? I have it! Amazing!
え、じゃあこれ開けれる？ギターもらえるの？坂本？せーの、ガチャ！
Eh, then can I open this? Can I get a guitar? Sakamata? Ready, open!
どうだ。ぶっちゃけ船長をつかまえたく ない
How's that? To be honest, I don't want to catch the captain.
おおー！すごい！いいんですか、これ！えー！あざまーす！入ってんだ！かっこよくない！？すごい！ギターもらえたー！
Oooh! Amazing! Is this okay?! Thanks so much! It's in there! Isn't it cool?! Amazing! I got a guitar!
では、次の曲、ギターを引きながらいきたいと思います！いきたいと思います！聞いてください、「パーフェクトクライム」！
Now, for the next song, I'd like to go while playing the guitar! Please listen, "Perfect Crime"!
あたしのブラックリストです
It's my blacklist.
愛していたのです
I loved you.
嫌いな人なのです
You're someone I hate.
あたしだけに優しい
Kind only to me...
あたしを可愛いと言ってくれる
You tell me I'm cute,
あたしのこと一番と言ってくれる
and that I'm your number one.
あたししか愛せないはず
You should only be able to love me.
あたしを綺麗にしてくれる あたしの為に死ね
You make me beautiful—die for my sake!
愛が愛しい
Love is so dear...
愛してそうして壊す
Love, and then destroy.
あたしがいないと眠れない
You can't sleep if I'm not here,
あたしの声を聞かないと生きられない
and you can't live without my voice.
あたしにしか縋れないはず
You should only lean on me.
あたしの為に生まれてきたならあたしの為に死ねよ
If you were born for me, die for my sake!
愛が愛しい
Love is so dear...
病める時も健やかなる時も
In sickness and in health,
富める時も貧しき時も
in wealth and in poverty,
愛し敬い
to love and to cherish,
慈しむことを誓いますと言え
say you swear to adore me!
愛が愛しい
Love is so dear...
愛してそうして呪うの
Love, and then curse.
笑ってるけどどっかないてんだ
I'm smiling, but somewhere I'm crying.
とりあえずご褒美の日々だ
Anyway, these are days of reward.
思ってるけどずっと貯めてんだ
I've been thinking, but saving it up.
偽物の味の毒の愛が
Poisonous love tasting like a fake
すり減って濁って愛して自分
Wears thin and muddied, loving myself.
手立てそうやって誤魔化して不感症
That's how I stall and grow numb.
分かってたキスをしてみるけど
I try giving a known kiss, but
乾いた稼働体だってなるんだ
it turns out to be a dry moving body.
期待したこといいのもっとつまんないアスファルトのシンデレラ
Forget expectations, a boring asphalt Cinderella.
叶えたい消えてゆくんだここぽっこぽこの境界線
I want wishes to come true, fading on this bumpy boundary.
どれも世界だ叶えたい消えてゆくんだ
Every single one is a world, I want them to fade...
ぽっこぽこの境界線君だけにわ教えてもいいか
On this bumpy boundary line, can I teach only you?
Playing the role of myself
true method,
what am I,
a psycho?
I'm gone. Where? I don't recall.
Or maybe I chose not to know.
笑ってるけど
Smiling, yet
どっか泣いてんだ
crying somewhere inside.
痛味味ご褒美の非難
The taste of pain, a rewarding rebuke.
思ってるけどずっと溜めてんだ
Thinking it, yet holding it in all along.
蜜の味呪いの愛が
The taste of honey, a cursed love
すり減って濁ってあいラブじゅぶん
wearing down, turning murky—plenty of love.
いつだってそうやって籠もって不感症
Always shutting yourself away, becoming numb.
起き上がってキスをしてみるけど
You get up and try to share a kiss,
かいていかさぶた痛くなってんだ
but the scab starts hurting.
わがままに選んでぽいってして
Choosing selfishly, then tossing it aside,
理屈抜きで夢とか信じたい
wanting to believe in dreams without reason.
劣等でどうかしちゃうマリオネットなんかじゃない
I'm no marionette driven mad by inferiority.
描いてみたって本音は死んでいた
Even when I try to picture it, my true feelings were dead.
選びたい捨てたい
Wanting to choose, wanting to throw away—
歪んでいくんだ
it's all warping,
僕と僕との境界線
the boundary line between me and myself.
どれも正解でどれも不正解だ
Every answer is right, yet every one is wrong.
選びたい捨てたい
Wanting to choose, wanting to throw away—
歪んでいくんだ
it's all warping,
マリオネットだから
because I'm just a marionette.
期待残っていいねをもっと
Expectations remain, give me more likes.
つまんなあっそ表裏のシンデレラ
How boring, oh well—a two-faced Cinderella.
kanaetai kietai
Wanting it granted, wanting to vanish—
歪んでいくんだ
it's all warping,
僕と僕との境界線
the boundary line between me and myself.
どれも正解でどれも不正解だ
Every answer is right, yet every one is wrong.
kanaetai kietai
Wanting it granted, wanting to vanish—
歪んでいくんだ
it's all warping,
僕と僕との境界線
the boundary line between me and myself.
どれも正解でどれも不正解だ
Every answer is right, yet every one is wrong.
kanaetai kietai
Wanting it granted, wanting to vanish—
歪んでいくんだ
it's all warping,
僕と僕との境界線
the boundary line between me and myself.
どれも正解でどれも不正解だ
Every answer is right, yet every one is wrong.
erabitai sutetai
Wanting to choose, wanting to throw away—
歪んでいくんだ僕と僕との境界線
it's warping, the boundary between me and myself.
君だけに教えてもっかい
I'll tell only you, one more time.
はあ、ありがとうございます、死ぬ...
Haah, thank you so much, I'm dying...
死ねやこれもう、
I'm gonna die from this,
とんでもなくね。あの息切れしてしまうが、
seriously. I'm completely out of breath,
でもどうだった？見ちゃいよかったでしょ？
but how was it? Wasn't it great?
めちゃくちゃかっこよかったでしょ？え、ギターに感謝いたします。
Wasn't it super cool? Huge thanks to the guitar.
え、ギタリストかっこよかったにゃと、ございます。
And huge thanks to the cool guitarist, meow.
じゃあちょっと、このね、実実は気づかなかったかもしれないですけど、左右...
Now, you might not have noticed this, but on the left and right...
見ててください。お立ち台があったりとかね。
take a look. There are raised platforms,
そして今回なんとですね、ええ、ベースを弾いてくださったり、ドラムを叩いてくださり、本当ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
and this time, we even had someone play bass and drums for us. Thank you so much!
ではちょっと、こちらのね、お立ち台に上りたいなって思うんで、見てみて。ベストといえばこれだよねみたいな感じの。
Now, I want to step up onto this platform here, so take a look. This is what you'd call the best look, right?
どーあ？
How is it?
イエーイ！かっこいいっしょ！このちょっとさ、高いところから弾く感じも、めっちゃいいじゃん。
Yay! Pretty cool, right? Playing from up high like this feels amazing.
ああみんな！オーディエンスちゃんありがとう！こっちののみんなもありがとう！
Ah everyone! Audience-chan, thank you! Everyone here, thank you too!
あっちののみんなにも行き...
I'll go over to everyone over there too—
ちょっと、はらし、行くぜ。こっちだ！
wait, let's go. Over here!
あいみんな！こっちののみんなもどうだ？盛り上がったか？ありがとう！
Hey everyone! How are you guys over here? Did you get hyped? Thank you!
めちゃめちゃギターかっこよかったでしょ？本当にね、かっこいいギターもらえて嬉しいです。
The guitar was super cool, right? I'm so happy to receive such a cool guitar.
うれしいです、さかまたお誕生日プレゼントありがとうございます！本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you for the Sakamata birthday presents! I'm so happy, truly thank you.
ではね、このあとグッズ紹介したいと思いますので、一旦ちょっとギター置いてしか...置きまして、ちょっと...お貸しください。
Now, I'd like to introduce the merchandise next, so I'll put my guitar down for a second...
おきましたーー！
I'm back!
ということですね、ええ、今回沙花叉クロエ生誕祭のグッズが出まーす！こちらでーす！視聴者、じょうじょうじょうじょう...
So, um, this time, merchandise for Sakamata Chloe's birthday festival is coming out! Here it is! Audience, look...
さかまたクロエ誕生日記念2023、5月18日販売開始！誕生日記念フルセット、ありがとうございます。テーマはお誕生日となっておりまして、フィーバーさかまたです！
Sakamata Chloe Birthday Commemoration 2023, on sale May 18th! Birthday Commemoration Full Set, thank you! The theme is birthdays, and it's Fever Sakamata!
今回はね、色々なシークレットさんたちに手に取ってほしくて、お求めやすい価格になっておりまーす！
This time, I wanted various secret-sans to be able to get their hands on it, so it's priced affordably.
ではちょっと、1個ずつね、説明していきたいと思います。
Now, let's go through and explain them one by one.
まずは、こちら！
First off, this one!
どうぞ。
Here you go.
飼育員証明書です。
It's the zookeeper certificate.
えー、沙花叉の飼育員証明書、えー、こちら
Um, Sakamata's zookeeper certificate, um, this
通勤通学のパスケースや社員証などね、
for commuter passes or employee ID cards,
あのぶら下げてあるあれの中にぜひ入れてください。
please put it inside that thing you hang up.
裏側にはね沙花叉が名前一応書いておきましたので
On the back, Sakamata wrote her name just in case,
よろしくお願いします。
so please take care of it.
さあ、続いてこちら！
Now, moving on to this!
リボンモチーフキーリングとはなっております。
It is a ribbon motif keychain.
こちら可愛いよね。
Isn't this cute?
え、沙花叉の衣装にあるリボンのキーリングです。
It's a ribbon keychain from Sakamata's outfit.
これ実はいろんなところにあるんですけどちょっと探してみてください。
It's actually in various places, so try looking for it.
どこだろう、どこだろう、どこどこだろう、探してね。
Where could it be, where could it be, where, where could it be, go find it.
そしてですね、鍵だけじゃなくてね、鞄とかにもねつけてもおしゃれな感じになると思いますので
And also, I think it'll look stylish if you attach it not just to keys, but to bags and things too,
ぜひとも、いい感じのさりげないグッズなのでつけてみてください。
so please do try attaching it since it's a nice, subtle piece of merch.
そしてボイスでございます、どうぞ！
And we also have voice tracks, here you go!
え、記念ボイス最高に激アツな誕生日ということでぜひ聞いてください。
Um, the commemorative voice is "My Hottest Birthday Ever," so please listen to it.
どんな内容なんだいって。
You might wonder what kind of content it is.
もちろんね、フルセットもご用意させていただいております。どうぞ！
Of course, we've also prepared a full set. Here you go!
全部セットをコンプしていただきますと、
If you purchase the complete set,
え、特典として複製サインに一言メッセージを直筆で書きたいと思います。
um, as a bonus, I'd like to handwrite a short message on the replicated autograph.
え、コンプ特典ボイスはですね、通常ボイスと別にねもう一個ついてくる君と最高の時間というボイスになっておりますので
Um, the complete bonus voice track is a separate voice from the regular one called "You and the Best Time,"
ぜひとも皆さんよろしくお願いいたします。
so everyone, please look forward to it.
えい、えい、えい、えい、10時から始まっているので
Yep, yep, yep, yep, it starts at 10:00,
よろしくお願いします。
so please check it out.
そして、次が最後の曲になるということで、みんなこの曲ね、ちょっと聞いたらびっくりすると思うんですけれど、
And, since the next is the final song, everyone, you'll probably be surprised when you hear this song,
ちょっとみんながびっくりしてくれるのワクワク期待しながら歌いたいと思います。
but I want to sing it while eagerly anticipating your surprise.
では、聞いてください。パライライズ。
Now, please listen. Paralyze.
調子合わせて笑う その度に嘲笑う
Laughing along to match the mood, sneering every time.
もう一人の自分が居る パパパライライズ
Another version of myself is there, Pa-pa-paralyze.
超幸せなふりも 傷ついてるふりも
Whether acting super happy or acting hurt,
見透かされてるような パパパライライズ
It feels like it's all seen right through, Pa-pa-paralyze.
自己嫌悪ならいつでも いつも いつも
Self-loathing, always, always, always,
自嘲するにもおそるおそる
Timidly self-deprecating,
スランバー 今夜はスリーパー
slumber, tonight I'm a sleeper.
明日またノックしてノックしてよ
Knock and knock again tomorrow.
大嫌いなんだよ泥汚れ
I hate dirt and grime so much.
ハローハロー心音
Hello, hello, heartbeat,
自分の羽音 かじり笑う
biting and laughing at the sound of my own wings,
鏡越しのOh Oh グラスホッパー
Through the mirror, Oh Oh grasshopper,
それで結構共存可能？不可能？
Is coexistence fine with that? Possible? Impossible?
途方に暮れ 飽きが来たら
When you're at your wits' end and get bored,
パパパライライズ麻痺させて
Pa-pa-paralyze, numb it out.
ラウンドアバウト メズマライズ 探し物に狂ってアップサイドダウン
Roundabout, mesmerize, going crazy in search of things, upside down.
だっつったらララバイ 自分同士パラライズ
If so, lullaby, paralyze between ourselves.
自己KOするいつかいつかいつか
Self-KO-ing someday, someday, someday.
遠目に見れば喜劇悲劇
Seen from afar, it's a comedy, a tragedy.
涙はいつも琥珀みたい
Tears are always like amber.
ほらノックしてノックしてよ
Come on, knock and knock again.
大嫌いなんだよ泥汚れ
I hate dirt and grime so much.
ハローハロー心音
Hello, hello, heartbeat,
自分の羽音 かじり笑う
biting and laughing at the sound of my own wings,
鏡越しのOh Oh グラスホッパー
Through the mirror, Oh Oh grasshopper,
それで結構共存可能？不可能？
Is coexistence fine with that? Possible? Impossible?
途方に暮れ 飽きが来たら
When you're at your wits' end and get bored,
パパパライライズ麻痺させて
Pa-pa-paralyze, numb it out.
それは切ないソナタ
That is a sorrowful sonata.
夜を深く泳いだら
If you swim deep into the night,
三日月の香りのする命を引っ掻いて
Scratching at the life that smells of a crescent moon,
CRY GONNA CRY
獰猛にまたたく
Twinkling fiercely,
パラライズ パラライズ共存可能？不可能？
Paralyze, paralyze, coexistence possible? Impossible?
パパパライライズ麻痺させて
Pa-pa-paralyze, numb it out.
パパパライライズ And lies
Pa-pa-paralyze And lies
パラライズ
Paralyze
はい、ということで今歌いました
Yes, so I just sang
新オリジナル曲のパラライズがですね、
my new original song, "Paralyze."
この後10時15分からプレミア公開になります。
It will premiere at 10:15 PM after this!
お楽しみに！みんな応援してくれてありがとう！
Look forward to it! Thank you everyone for your support!
ご馳走様でした！
Thanks for everything!
ありがとう！ばいばーい！ありがとう！
Thank you! Bye-bye! Thank you!